# pedro almeida

## <web\_developer/>

Praça 9 de abril nº 49 2º dto • 4400-422 • Porto

**BIRTHDATE 8.12.84 • Nº CC** 12772939

CELL (351) 912 746 621 • E-MAIL pedrocoelhoalmeida@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO pmcalmeida.github.io/portfolio • LINKED IN pt.linkedin.com/pub/pedro-79/281/135

#### **PROFILE**

**Senior web developer** with 6+ years of experience, with a vast know-how in the development, integration and business implementation of tailor-made web based applications such as websites, CMS, CRM, and other information systems.

**Highly skilled in translating to code** any design for frontend or backend web applications, on multiple devices. Able to create the user experiences and workflow, using a rigorous approach of the latest standards of HTML and CSS rules and SEO practices, applying various design patterns, such as MVC structures, responsive grids, bootstrapping, templating, frameworks and plugins.

**Always seeking to adapt** to new agile development methodologies and frameworks. Open to challenges and complex projects, with excellent analytic and problem solving skills.

**Good verbal and written communication skills**. Able to work, interact and coordinate nimbly as a team to find the most viable solutions in terms of resources and time. Manage, plan and estimate a project development cycle in order act quickly to make decisions under pressure and meet goals and demands.

**Passion in building** inspiring, sophisticated, functional and secure applications that are at the stat of the art of web technology, which result in intuitive and appealing products for the end user.

#### LOOKING FOR

Integrate an organized, social and fun work environment with well-defined objectives and methodologies, with freedom and responsibility. Develop exceptional web applications and be able to push my skills and capabilities to the next level.

......

INTERESTS Android and iOS, open source software, design, gadgets, hardware, videogames, hardware, music, movies and series, traveling.

SITUATION Currently employed with a fixed term contract at Yap Technologies.

AVAILABILITY Available to start from the 5<sup>th</sup> of January of 2015.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Curso de Especialização Tecnológica Nível IV (Bachelor) em Tecnologias e Programação de Sistemas de Informação (Information Technology)

Escola Superior Aveiro Norte, Universidade de Aveiro Graduated 2008

## Curso Tecnológico de Informática (High School)

Escola Secundária José Estevão, Aveiro Graduated 2004

MAIN SKILLS PHP5 Javascript Jquery HTML(5) CSS(3)

MySQL PostgreSQL SQL Server

JqueryUI Boostrap Semantic UI Zend Framework Twig PEAR

#### OTHER SKILLS

Extensive knowledge of Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer and Safari debugging tools

Use of Git based repositories for version control

Configuration of Apache 2 web servers in Linux/Windows machines

General knowledge of multimedia tools like Adobe Photoshop, Fireworks and Flash.

Basic familiarity with some web frameworks such as Angular JS, node.js, SASS, Yii, Laravel, Foundation, Google Polymer.

Developing in Eclipse IDE and installation and configuration of Linux Ubuntu distributions

Knowledge of other server side OOP programing languages such as Java, Python, C#.net, ASP.net.

Production of Excell style sheets, word documentation and powerpoint presentations.

Database modeling in Microsoft Visio and Dia (open source)

## LANGUAGE

Portuguese native

English fluent written and spoken

Spanish elementary

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend / Yap Technologies - Porto | 04/2014 - Present day

Research and development – www.frontend.pt

Fixed term contract. Development of the multi platform (ios, android, desktop) web based digital publishing platform - PP3, both frontend and backend, analytics and page editor platform built upon HTML5, CSS3, Semantic UI, Jquery UI and Twig template, built on the Zend Framework for an MVC structured application and REST API.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## MagicBrain OFPG Lda - Coimbra | 01/2011 - 03/2014

Web developer and systems analyst – www.magicbrain.pt

Permanent contract. Developed and maintained several websites for e-commerce and promotion of products and services built upon several web technologies such as JQuery/JQuery UI, HTML5 and CSS3.

Implemented a CMS structured in MVC made from scratch in PHP5 and tailormade to the needs and specifications of each client. This includes content, client and newsletter managements and analytics reports as other features.

CRM sales and stock management web platform integrated with PHC financial software, backed by CRUD generated web service built on PHPWsdl, for the Stricker SA europe website.

## Vegas Cosmetics | 2010

Freelance commercial website - <a href="www.vegascosmetics.pt">www.vegascosmetics.pt</a>
Developed with PHP, MySQL, Javascript/Prototype, HTML and CSS.

# Micro I/O Serviços de Electrónica Lda – Aveiro | 01/2009 – 02/2011 Web developer – <a href="https://www.microio.pt">www.microio.pt</a>

Fixed term contract. Developed several web based products and applications within the purpose of school account, canteen, queue and assiduity management.

Built on PHP5, XAJAX, HTML, CSS and Javascript/Prototype with the resource data of a SOAP XML request webservice or Postgres/MySQL database.

#### Professional internship at Micro I/O – Aveiro | 06/2008 – 12/2008

SIGE3 Portal, web based application for school card and account management. Built on PHP5, HTML, CSS and Javascript with the resource of a SOAP XML request webservice.

#### Internship at Proxima SI – Aveiro | 2005

Development of institutional website and CMS proposal in PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript.